Preliminary Inventory to the Free Society Association Records, 1964-1968
Hoover Institution Archives
Free Society Association Records,
1964-1968
80052
Free Society Association
18 manuscript boxes, 6 phonotapes (7.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, speeches, press releases, and financial records, relating to American politics.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
United States--Politics and government.; United States--Politics and government--1963-1969.; Conservatism.; Phonotapes.
Container List
- A-B (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
- American Conservative Union
- Americans for Conservative Education
- Annis, Edward R.
- Arnold, W. A.
- Art work and plates
- Audit reports
- Baroody, William
- Bauer, Hazel U.
- Bork, Robert H.
- Brandt, Karl E.
- Brozen, Yale
- Brunsdale, Anne E.
  - Personnel records
  - Reading file
    - 1966
    - 1967
- Bryan, D. Tennant
- Burch, Dean
- By-laws and articles of incorporation
- C-D (miscellaneous)
- Campaign, 1964
- Campbell, W. Glenn
- Cervino, Silvia
- Charlottesville, Va., meeting, May 10, 1966 (Box 2)
- Chase, Jamie S.
- Chicago meeting, May 17, 1966
- Cole, Mrs. Louis S., Jr.
- College program
- Conservative Book Club
- Conservative organizations
- Constitution
- Consultants
- Correspondence (miscellaneous)
- Crawford, Ronald (Box 3)
  - Correspondence
  - Memoranda to
  - Reading file
    - May-June 1966
    - Oct.-Nov. 1966
    - Jan.-July 1967
- Dalton, Ruby
  - Memoranda
  - Personnel records
- Darracott, Mr. and Mrs. Joseph G.
- Davenport, John
- Dinner meetings, Future
- Directories
- Drachkovitch, Milorad
- E-F (miscellaneous)
- Editorial Board
- Evans, M. Stanton
- Financial data
- Founders Dinners
  - New York, May 25, 1966
  - Philadelphia, Apr. 19, 1966
- Frank R. Lee and Associates
- Friedman, Milton F.
- G-H (miscellaneous)
- Galvin, Robert W.
- Garvey Foundation
- Goldwater, Barry (Box 4)
  - Campaign speeches
    - Oct. 13, 1963-Feb. 12, 1964
    - Feb. 19-June 25, 1964
    - July 10-Sept. 30, 1964
    - Oct. 1-20, 1964 (Box 5)
    - Oct. 21, 1964-Jan. 22, 1965
  - Correspondence
  - Pictures
  - Reading file
    - May-Sept. 1966
    - Oct.-Nov. 1966
    - Jan.-July 1967 (Box 6)
    - Aug.-Nov. 1967
    - Jan.-Apr. 1968
  - Speeches, 1966
- Governors' Conference, Denver, May 27-28, 1966
- Grenier, John
- Hawkins, Jean B.
  - Correspondence
  - Personnel records
- Henle, Ray
- Hoover, Allan
- Howard, John A.
- Human Events
- Human interest letters
- I-J (miscellaneous)
- Indiana
- Ingersoll Foundation
- Jergens, Andrew (Box 7)
- Job applications, 1966
- John Birch Society
- Johnson, R. W.
- K-L (miscellaneous)
- Kilpatrick, James J.
- Kitchel, Denison
  - Correspondence re speeches
  - General
  - Letters re tax exemption
  - Nashville trip
  - Reading file
    - July-Aug. 1965
    - May-June 1966
    - July-Oct. 1966
    - Oct.-Nov. 1966 (Box 8)
    - Jan.-July 1967
    - Aug.-Dec. 1967
    - Jan.-Feb. 1968
  - Speech requests
  - Speeches
- Liberal Republican groups
- Libraries
  - 1965
  - 1966
  - 1967
  - 1968
- Lichenstein, Charles M. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence
  - Memoranda by
  - Memoranda to
  - Personnel records
  - Reading file
    - May-Sept. 1966
    - Oct.-Dec. 1966
    - Jan.-July 1967
    - Aug.-Dec. 1967
    - Jan.-June 1968 (Box 10)
- Luce, Clare Boothe
- M-N (miscellaneous)
- McCune, Charles
- McManus, Brian J.
- Mailing services
  - Correspondence
  - Prices
- Maytag, L. B., Jr.
- Membership survey, Apr. 1966
- Memoranda, Inter-office
- Milbank, Jeremiah F.
- Miscellany
- Moley, Raymond (Box 11)
- Mont Pelerin Society
  - Stresa, Italy, 1965
  - Tokyo, 1966
- Morrison, R. G.
- Moss, Alice F.
- Mote, Lynn E.
  - Personnel records
  - Reading file, 1966
- Mynatt, Fred
- National Review
- New York dinner, Oct. 5, 1966
- New York rally, June 29, 1966
- Newsletter (Box 12)
- Newsmakers
- Newspapers
- Nielsen, Arthur C.
- Niemeyer, Gerhart
- Nixon, Richard M.
- North Carolina fund soliciting
- Nutter, Warren
- O-P (miscellaneous)
- Organization
  - Correspondence
  - General
  - Memoranda
- Parry, Stanley
- Part-time employees
- Paton, William A.
- Payroll records, 1965
- Pew, John G.
- Pictures
- Pitcairn family
- Press releases (Box 13)
  - June 17, 1965
  - June-Dec. 1965
  - Jan.-Feb. 1966
  - Mar.-Apr. 1966
  - May-Sept. 1966
  - Oct.-Dec. 1966
  - Mar.-May 1967
- Prudential Employee Security Program (Box 14)
- Public interest letters
- Public relations
  - General
  - Press
  - Radio and television
- Publications of the Free Society Association
- Publications of others
- Q-R (miscellaneous) (Box 15)
- Radford, Arthur W.
- Radio and television
- Radio New York Worldwide
- Reading file, Miscellaneous
  - May-Sept. 1966
  - Oct.-Nov. 1966
  - Jan.-July 1967
- Republican National Committee
- Ripon Society
- S-T (miscellaneous)
- School letters
- South Vietnam pamphlet
- Stationery items
- Stokes, William
- Strauss, Lewis L.
- Survey of membership
- Swain List Management
- Swim, Dudley
- Taber, Dorothy (Box 16)
- Tang, Jean C.
- Tax-exempt status
  - Application
  - Follow-up inquiries
  - Guides
  - Special memorandum
- Taxes - District of Columbia
- Taxes, Unemployment compensation
- Telephone and telegraph
- Timolat, Louis K. (Box 17)
- Travel and lodging, 1966
- Trustees
  - Correspondence
    - 1965
    - 1966
    - 1967
  - Meeting, Feb. 24, 1966
  - Memoranda
- Turndowns
- Union Trust Company
- United Republicans of California
- V.I.P. compliments
- Virtue, Philip M.
- Volunteers
- W-Z (miscellaneous)
- Ware, Richard A.
- White, Margareta E.
- Xerox
- Young Americans for Freedom
- Young Republicans
- New Federalist Papers (Proposed publication) (Box 18)
  - Drafts
  - General
  - Requests
- "The Minimum Wage and Unemployment," discussion between Yale Brozen and Milton Friedman, Nov. 7, 1965 (Phonotape Phonotape 1-2)
- Free Society Association meeting, Chicago, May 17, 1966 (Phonotape Phonotape 3-4)
- Unidentified (Phonotape Phonotape 5-6)